Jacob Appelbaum: So, thanks very much to the
guy who brought me a Mate.
I learned his name is Alexander.
It's never a good idea to take drugs from
strangers,
so I introduced myself before I drank it - thank
you.
First I wanted to say that following up after
Glenn Greenwald is a great honor and a really
difficult thing to do, that's a really tough
act to follow, and he's pretty much one of,
I think, our heroes.
So, it's really great to be able to share
the stage with him, even for just a brief
moment. And I wanted to do something a little
unconventional when we started and Roger agreed.
Which is that we want people who have questions
- since I suspect some things happened this
year that arouse a lot of questions in people
- we'd like you to write those questions down,
pass them to an Angel or to just bring them
to the front of the stage as soon as possible
during the talk, so that we can answer as
many of your questions as is possible.
This is a lot of stuff that happened, there's
a lot of confusion, and we wanna make sure
that people feel like we are actually answering
those questions in a useful way.
And if you wanna do that, it'd be great, and
otherwise, we're gonna try to have the second
half of our talk be mostly space for questioning.
So with that, here is Roger.
Roger Dingledine: Okay, so, a lot of things
have happened over this past year,
and we're gonna try and cover as many of them
as we can.
Here's a great quote from either NSA or GCHQ,
I'm actually not sure which one it is.
But we're gonna start a little bit earlier
in the process than this and work our way
up to that.
So, we're in a war, or rather, conflict of
perception here. There are a lot - I mean,
you saw Glenn's talk earlier - there are a
lot of large media organisations out there
that are trying to present Tor in lots of
different ways,
and we all here understand the value that
Tor provides to the world, but there are a
growing number of people around the world
who are learning about Tor not from our website,
or from seeing one of these talks or from
learning it from somebody who uses it and
teaches them how to use it.
But they read the Time Magazine or Economist
or whatever the mainstream newspapers are,
and part of our challenge is how do we help
you, and help the rest of the world do outreach
and education, so that people can understand
what Tor is for and how it works and what
sorts of people actually use it.
So, for example, GCHQ has been given instructions
to try to kill Tor by, I mean, who knows,
maybe they thought of it on their own, maybe
we can imagine some nearby governments asked
them to do it. And part of the challenge...
they say "we have to kill it because of child
porn".
And it turns out that we actually do know
that some people around the world are using
Tor for child porn. For example, we have talked
to a lot of federal agencies who use Tor to
fetch child porn. [subdued laughter]
I talked to people in the FBI who use Tor
every day to safely reach the websites that
they want to investigate.
The most crazy example of this is actually
the Internet Watch Foundation. How many people
here have heard of the Internet Watch Foundation?
I see a very small number of hands.
They are the censorship wing of the British
government. They are the sort of quasi-government
organisation who is tasked with coming up
with the blacklist for the internet for England.
And, we got e-mail from them a few years ago,
saying - not what you'd expect, you'd expect
"Hey, can you please shut this thing down,
can you turn it off, it's a big hassle for
us." - the question they asked me was: "How
can we make Tor faster?" [laughter, claps]
It turns out that they need Tor, because people
report URLs to them, they need to fetch them
somehow. It turns out that when you go the
URL with the allegedly bad stuff on it and
you're coming from the Internet Watch Foundation's
IP-address, they give you kittens. [laughter]
Who would have known? [laughter, applause]
So it turns out that these censors need an
anonymity system in order to censor their
internet. [laughter] Fun times.
So another challenge here: at the same point,
one of my side hobbies is teaching law enforcement
how the internet works, and how security works
and how Tor works.
So, yeah, their job does suck, but it's actually
not our fault that their job sucks. There
are a lot of different challenges to successfully
being a good, honest law enforcement person
these days.
So, for example, I went to Amsterdam and Brussels
in January of this past year to try to teach
various law enforcement groups.
And I ended up having a four-hour debate with
the Dutch regional police, and then another
four-hour debate with a Belgian cybercrime
unit and then another four-hour debate with
the Dutch national police.
And, there are a lot of good-meaning smart
people in each of these organisations, but
they end up, as a group, doing sometimes quite
bad things.
So part of our challenge is: how do we teach
them that Tor is not the enemy for them?
And there are a couple of stories that I've
been trying to refine using on them. One of
them they always pull out, the "But what about
child porn? What about bad people? What about
some creep using Tor to do bad things?".
And one of the arguments that I tried on them
was, “Okay, so on the one hand we have a
girl in Syria who is alive right now because
of Tor. Because her family was able to communicate
safely and the Syrian military didn’t break
in and murder all of them."
"On the other hand, we have a girl in America
who is getting hassled by some creep on the
internet who is stalking her over Tor."
So the question is, how do we balance, how
do we value these things? How do we assign
a value to the girl in Syria and how do we
assign a value to the girl in America so that
we can decide which one of these is more important?
And actually the answer is, you don’t get
to make that choice, that’s not the right
question to ask.
Because if we take Tor away from the girl
in Syria, she’s going to die. If we take
Tor away from the creep in America, he’s
got a lot of other options for how he can
be a creep and start stalking people.
So if you’re a bad person, for various definitions
of bad person, and you’re willing to break
laws or go around social norms, you’ve got
a lot of other options besides what Tor provides.
Whereas there are very few tools out there
like Tor for honest, I'd like to say law-abiding,
but let's go with civilization-abiding citizens
out there.
Jacob Appelbaum: And it’s important to understand
that this hypothetical thing is actually also
true for certain values.
So at our Tor developer meeting that we had
in Munich recently, that Syrian woman came
to us, and thanked us for Tor. She said,
I’m from a city called Homs. You might have
heard about it, it’s not a city anymore.
I used Tor. My family used Tor. We were able
to keep ourselves safe on the internet thanks
to Tor.
So I wanted to come here to Munich to tell
you this. Thank you for the work that you’re
doing.
And for people who - this was their first
dev meeting - they were completely blown away
to meet this person.
- 'Wow, the stuff that we're working on, it
really does matter, there are real people
behind it.'
And, I think, we were all really touched by
it, and all of us know someone who has been
on the receiving end of people being jerks
on the internet.
So this is a real thing where there are real
people involved, and it's really important
to understand that if you remove the option
for that woman in Syria
- or you here in Germany, now that we know
what Edward Snowden has told the world -
those bad guys, those jerks, for different
values of that,
they always have options.
But very rarely do all of us have options
that will actually keep us safe.
And Tor is certainly not the only one, but
right now, and we hope in this talk you'll
see that we're making the right tradeoff by
working on Tor.
[Roger Dingledine]
One of the other talks that I give to them,
one of the other stories that I give to them,
one of the big questions they always ask me
is: "But what about terrorists? Aren't you
helping terrorists?"
And we, we can and we should talk about "What
do you mean by terrorists?" because in China
they have a very different definition of terrorists
and in Ghaza they have a very different definition
of terrorists,
and in America, they are always thinking of
a small number of people in some Middle-Eastern
country who are trying to blow up buildings
or something -
[Jacob Appelbaum]
Mohamed Badguy, I think is his name.
[Roger Dingledine]
Yes, that -
[Jacob Appelbaum]
In the NSA slides.
[Roger Dingledine]
Yes.
So, scenario one: I want to build a tool that
works for millions of people, it will work
for the next year, and I can tell you how
it works, so you can help me evaluate it.
That's Tor's problem.
Scenario two: I want to build a tool that
will work for the next two weeks, it will
work for 20 people and I'm not going to tell
you about it.
There are so many more ways of solving scenario
two than solving scenario one.
The bad guys for all sorts of definitions,
the bad guys have a lot more options on how
they can keep safe. They don't have to scale,
it doesn't have to last forever, they don't
want peer review, they don't want anybody
to even know that it's happening.
So the challenge that Tor has is that we wanna
build something that works for everybody and
that everybody can analyze and learn about.
That's a much harder problem, there are far
fewer ways of solving that.
So, the terrorists, they got a lot of options.
That sucks. We need to build tools that can
keep the rest of the world save.
[Jacob Appelbaum]
And it's important, really, to try to have
some good rethorical arguments, I think. I
mean, we sort of put a few facts up here.
One interesting point to mention is that people
who really don't want anonymity to exist in
a practical sense, maybe not even in a theoretical,
human rights sense either, but definitely
in a practical sense, they're not really having
honest conversations about it.
For example, this DOJ study, the Department
of Justice in the United States, they actually
started to do a study where they classified
traffic leaving Tor exit nodes.
Which is interesting - that they were basically
probably wiretapping an exit node to do that
study, I wonder how they went about that - but
nonetheless, they came up with the number
of three percent of the traffic being bad
and then they aborted the study because they
received many DMCA takedown notices. [laughter]
[Roger Dingledine]
Yes, they -
[Jacob Appelbaum]
Apparently even the DMCA is a problem to finding
out answers. [unintelligible]
[Roger Dingledine, interrupts]
They asked a university to run the Tor exit
for them and they were just starting out doing
their study, and then the university started
getting DMCA takedowns and said:
"Well, we have to stop, the lawyers told us
to stop!", and the Department of Justice said:
"We're the Department of Justice, keep doing
it.", and then they turned it off. [laughter]
So, not sure how the balance of power goes
there, but the initial results they were looking
towards were about three percent of the traffic
coming out of that Tor exit node was bad,
but I haven't figured out what they mean by
"bad". But I'll take it if it's three percent.
[Jacob Appelbaum]
Jake dislikes the term 'war' when talking
about the internet. The BBC has articles on
their website on using Tor + Silk Road to
buy drugs. We don't do that - even though
Bitcoin is amazing, it's not anonymous. BBC
has a 'man-bite-dog'-approach, they run with
everything which looks a bit interesting.
We dont wan tthat: we want for every person
to have the right and possiblity to express
themselves. When the BBC ran a story about
Tor, everyone was thankful, then they posted
another article on Tor+Silk Road.
That has a serious problem, the war on drugs
becomes intertwined with the war on Tor. Agent
who showed 'massive drop ' in Tor traffic
after Silk Road shut down, was with US govt.
Such publicty always leads to drop, not necessarily
directly connected. Then they checked the
data, see graph, and saw almost no drop. Can
you guess where the drop the agent talks about
occurred? It didn't go down by 50%. Agent
waswrong. Qrrow where it would have dropped
according to agent. Here's a graph of the
overall network growth over the past three
years. Multiple relays added after Snowden
revelations.
The Dark Web (or other scary names) is media
trying to produce as many articles as they
can. Definitions range from 'every webpage
that Google can't index' (so every govt database,
etc), '98% of pages are in dark web', 'only
way to access dark web is through Tor'. These
statements together sell many articles, people
are shocked.
REality is that it's not actually the case.
People here know this: these stories are clickbait'.
Few hands go up about Tor hidden se
(lost connection for a minute)
These things also bring out much negative
attention. The Freedom Hosting was relentlessly
attacked, because the topics the other sites
have pull on peoples' hearts in a big way.
First issue of WikiLeaks was really hard on
many people. The news also picks up on that
in negative ways. You could call that a cultural
conflict.
I heard from a DEA person who was involved
in Farmer's Market takedown. Old drug webiste,
Tor was not involved. DEA wanted to take it
down. They sent a letter to take it down,
[...]
People used hushmail. Year or two later people
discovered Tor. SIx months later there were
all these newspaper articles about how Tor
hidden services are broken. They were using
PayPal directly. Story is 'don 't use Hushmail'.
Don't use lawful interception-compliant or
backdoored services, such as Hushmail, especially
if you traffic drugs.
As a result, we have seen some pretty crazy
stuff happen. In this case, this year we saw
one of the most intersting exploits we have
seen deployed againts a broad scale of users.
Not sure who was behind it. Claimed by an
FBI agent, IP space may be NSA-owned. Exploit
in Firefox. Traditionally, if you don't use
Tor, they go to your house and install gear
or intercept your connection. They find out
who you are, target you, serve you an exploit.
Here, they had taken over a Tor hidden service
and explited old versions of Tor browser.
Not used as fresh zero-day. When the FBI did
this, they give this exploit to other regimes
as well. They would like to be able to be
more up to speed with Firefox. HOwever, there
is still desynchronisation. They have probably
hired some people from this community - fuck
you- and have them write their exploits.
Now we're looking into Chrome, which has a
differen t and sometimes more secure architecture.
We're hoping to work on using Chrome, anyone
want to help? Please do.
Diversity of funding - a lot of funding comes
from governmetns. There are ten things we
want to work on, if you want to fund one of
those ten, you can focus our interests. Government
funding helps to do many cool things. people
can be payed to work on Tor, on the other
hand governments can influence our priorities.
We will not put backdoors in Tor.
People have approached us to put backdoors
in Tor. It is a serious committment to not
do this. We fix everything as soon as we find
out that something is wrong. There are people
who have tried to have us change that committment.
When we say we are non-profit, they are dumbfounded.
US DoJ person approached, Congress has given
us right to backdoor everything, you have
to make a backdoor so that we can use our
rights to surveil everybody. You abuse the
righst you have been given by our country.
Then they said they are nonprofit and the
conversation bascially ended. Part of what
they need to do: continue to make safe tools.
Everyone wants to help for anti-censorship,
noone wants to pay for better anonimyt. People
are often dependent on the anonimity Tor allows.
There is a tradeoff with a lot of our founders,
they don't like us as much when we say really
outrageaous thiings. We want funders who want
the same things as you and us: if you know
someone, please approach us.
It's easy to say we should not be political.
It's also crazy to say so, because the idea
of haveing free speech and freedom of information
is a very political idea. Especillay after
the summer of Snowden, we realize almost no
tools can resist NSA/GCHQ. They can't get
all Tor users, we made it very expensive for
them to do mass surveillance. Please note
that the solution is not partisan: all people
are equally good or bad. The common good of
every one having these rights protected is
an important thing to build and to have. That
is the best kind of political solution we
can have. We however need
[...]
We need everyone in the same network, diversity
of users. From a technical perspective, so
that they can keep each other safe. We all
get better when the others are involved. Having
Jake talk to LE is not the most effective
way. Lawyer said "Never miss a chance to shut
the fuck up". Therefore we instruct everybody:
corporations, civil righst groups, LE. We
need you to be involved and share the word
in your co
[...]
We're pretty good in fighting back against
policies and legal changes. If ISPs hate exit
relays, it becomes harder to run one. We're
doing ok in that respect. Third one we have
not focused on as much as we could. Growing
number of places are just rejecting Tor users.
Wikipedia, Skype. Microsoft hangs up on you
if you want to Skype, because of blacklist
from some company, they blakclist Tor exit
relays. We need help learning how to teach
all these companies to not judge users on
their IP adresses.
When a company does not want to give you location
anonimity, maybe there's a reason for that.
OFten they don't have metrics for not having
location data. In a few cases it's better
that Tor is blocked, because they don't allow
anonymous logins when Tor is allowed. We need
to show that it is the best thing right now.
We need people to help us understand the overlap
between the Tor community and their community
(especially Wikipedia). If Iḿ not abusive
on Wikipedia, I should be able to login anonymously.
Especially since the only way to anonymously
use wikipedia is through Tor.
The last point is this one (graph). People
started yelling 'IPO'. Aparrently, some person
signed up his entire botnet. It's good to
know scalability measures work. We had to
make some changes. Using elliptic curves as
really helped to lower work on the relasy.
If this had been a real attacker against the
Tor network, it probably would have been fatal.
Microsoft has the power to remove the things
they think are malicious. Tor clients on these
bots are often still installed. Botnet happening
in same time as Snowden revelations makes
it hard to assess the impact of these revelations
on Tor use. Bots connecting are a really serious
threat to the Tor network.
It would make it significantly harder to damage
the Tor network if more people were involved.
When talking of funding for better anonimity,
how much do you need? If you're wiilling to
fund it, it wuold be great if you could match
what government funders bring to the table.
Or as much money as you have, both are great.
If it ends up on the 2 million USD we have
no money for extras. We have to build all
sorts of tools that are not directly related
to Tor. It's not enough to have Tor, hyou
need tools to work with Tor. We haven't really
experimented with that.
The NSA and GCHQ have decided that they don't
like anonimity and want to eradicate it. A
few exceptions. I will talk about this on
monday. On the Tor side, Quick Ant is a [...]. It
is recording data about TLS sessions, pulled
from a larger pile that is called FLYINGPIG.
That program is kind of scary, but not too
much. Quantum INsert is a scary man on the
side attack. FOXACID is a targeted attack,
sort of awatering hole attack. When you use
Tor they make your server redirect to their
malicious code and hit you. It took them eight
months to hit one Tor user. That's great.
It really takes much effort to hit one person,
they need that person to be caught.
Quantom Cookie is a program to retrieve other
browser connections to find out concurrent
browser activity. Then they would insert other
things the browser would request to see what
other activity you have. Solution is HTTPS
EVerywhere, whihc also allows session isolation.
On the other hand, not every website allows
TLS. The thing that makes it interseting is
that they do it at internet scale.
You would imaginge that not routing through
Five Eyes countries makes you safer. On the
other hand, in the Five Eyes countries you
have some protections. The key point to take
home is that every single person here has
the same problems if they're not useing Tor.
The story here is they look at Tor traffic
coming out of Tor relays
they don't know who it is.
On the one hand, they need borad attacks (not
targeted).
DNI sent out a press release that they are
never attacking US citizens. {...]James Platter
is an asshole (:) )
I talked to an NSA person a couple of weeks
ago ... You have to attack all non-Americans/
No, only if they are the person who we are
attacking. I wish we had 90000 Tor nodes,
that would be incredible. When the NSA ran
tor notdes, that was about a dozen.
They can watch your Tor relays, which is as
good as having their own relay. We should
not be worried they're runnning relays. It's
a concern, but the bigger concern is that
they're watching the whole internet. The problem
is not
so much are they running relays but how many
normal relays can they watch. A large adversary
like the NSA: a third? Half/ We don't know.
Who here uses a VPN or some kind of VPN service
[about 1/4]? This is a big problem, the hide-my-ass
problem. They basically promote their service
for revolution in Egupt, but turn around when
aimed at the UK.
We need to build decentralized systems
In some cases we know that VPN proxies have
data retion for 10-15 year, that 's bad news.
The news on VPNs is not in your favor.
What happens with this stuff?
It could be that the silk road fellow used
VPN.
It could also be that the NSA has tracked
him in some other way.
Parallel construction is a really serious
problem,
if we could expand Tor network, we would make
it significantly harder to do that.
We live in a world were intelligence services
and LE are merging together.
That is a sierious problem for Tor.
NSA is doing bad stuff, why should that affect
FBI?
They said they told the FBI. Do they anonymously
tip the FBI?
Is there a third party anonymous whistleblower?
From the FBI point of view, thats basically
the same.
We are able to adress some questions.
Summaries: We want to improve hidden services.
We want to make them strong, especially improve
performance.
The
more mainstream they become, the more use
we will be seeing.
It should be esay to use them.
The most important things for cypherpunks
to understand.
If you like, use Bitcoin.
If you want to give us lots of BItocins, do
not get dsicouraged.
In Noisy Square, there is
now
a talk on helping Tor.
We need you
to
teach other poeple on
why Tor
is important.
Thank you
[no time for Q/A left]