so now the next arc that we have here
for one hour from 8:30 till 9:30
as the Tor network
in interesting times I don't know how
many of you are familiar with the words
of Terry Pratchett
but anyways and another tough Terry
Pratt said
there is some the saying and may you
live in interesting times
that is actually occurs for someone that
u especially dislike because it usually
means that you're in a lot of trouble
so I guess who are very excited for this
year's Tour talk
by the everlasting Dream Team Jacob
Appelbaum
and proctor deals I'm there you go the
so on thanks very much to the guy who
brought me Mata had learned his name is
Alexander it's never good idea to take
drugs from strangers to introduce myself
up for a drink it
thank you com
for someone to say that following up
after Glenn Greenwald urs
a great honor and a really difficult
thing to do at a really tough act to
follow
and he's pretty much what I think our
heroes
so it's really great to be able to share
the stage with an even for just a brief
moment
and I want to do something a little
unconventional when we started and Roger
greed
which is that we want people who have
questions since I suspect something's
happened this year
there as a lot of questions and people
we'd like you to write those questions
down
passed into an angel or to just bring
them to the front of the stage as soon
as possible
during the talks so that we can answer
as many of your questions as possible
there's a lot of stuff that happened as
a lot of confusion and we want to make
sure that people
feel like we are actually answering
those questions and useful way
and if you wanna do that would be great
and otherwise we're gonna try to have
the second half HARDtalk be
mostly space for questioning so but
actors Roger
okay so a lot of things have happened
over this past year and we're gonna try
to cover
as many of them as we can here's a a
great quote for me either an essay or
GCHQ I'm actually
I'm not sure which one it is but we're
gonna start a little bit earlier in the
process than this and work your way up
to that
so we're in a war or rather conflict a
perception here
there are a lot mean you saw glenn's
talk earlier there are a lot of
large media organizations out there that
are trying to present
tower in lots of different ways and we
all here understand the value the tour
provides to the world
but there are a growing number of people
around the world who are learning about
or
not from our website or from seeing one
of these talks or from learning it from
somebody who uses it and teaches them
how to use it but they read the
time magazine or economist or whatever
the
mainstream on newspapers are and part of
our challenges
how do we help you and help the rest to
the world
do outreach and education so that people
can understand
what source for and how it works and and
what sort of people
actual use it so for example are GCHQ is
I has been given instructions to try to
kill tore by
I mean who knows maybe they thought it
on their own maybe we can imagine some
nearby governments ask them to do it
are and part in the challenge a they say
were
were we have to kill it because a trial
part and it turns out that we actually
do know that
some people around the world are using
tor for child porn
are for example we have talked to a lot
of federal agencies who used for
to fetch child porn I talk to people in
the FBI who used or every day to safely
reach the web sites that they want to
investigate I
the most crazy example if this is
actually the internet watch foundation
I how many people here have heard the
internet watch foundation I see a very
small number hands
they are the censorship weighing above
the British government
their the to require the government
organization who is tasked with coming
up with the black list for the internet
for England and we got an email from
them a few years ago
saying know you would expect you'd
expect hey can you please shut this
thing down can you turn it off its
it's a big hassle for us the question
that they asked me was
how can we make it or faster it turns
out that they need to our biggest
people report URL's to them they need to
fetch them somehow it turns out that
when you go to the URL with the
allegedly bad stuff on it
and you're coming from the internet
watch foundation site the address
they give you couldn't who would have
known
so
so it turns out that these sensors need
an anonymity system
in order to censor their internet fun
times
so another challenge here
a at the same point one on my side
hobbies is teaching law enforcement
I how the internet works and how
security works and how to our works
so I mean the other job does suck but
it's actually not our fault that their
job sucks
there are a lot of different challengers
to successfully being a
a good honest law enforcement person
these days so for example
I went to Amsterdam and Brussels in
January this past year to try to teach
various law-enforcement groups
and i ended up having a four-hour debate
with the Dutch Regional Police
and then another for our debate with the
I Belgian cyber crime unit
and then another four hour debate with
the Dutch national police and
there are a lot of good meaning smart
people in each of these organizations
but they end up
as a group doing are sometimes quite bad
thing
so part of our challenge is how do we
teach them that war is not the enemy
for them and there are couple stories
that I have been
trying to atone refined using on them
I love them they always pull out the but
what about child porn what about bad
people what about some creep using
toward to do bad things
a and one of the arguments that I tried
on them was ok it's on the one hand
we have a girl in Syria who is
alive right now because it or because
her family was able to communicate
safely
and the Syrian military didn't break in
and murder all of them on the other hand
we have a girl in America who is getting
hassled by some creep on the Internet
who was stalking her overt or so the
question is how do we
how do we balance how do we value these
things do we
how do we sign a value to the girl in
Syria how to assign a value to the girl
america
so that we can decide which one is more
important and actually the answer is
you don't get to make that choice that's
not the right question to ask
because if we take tore away from the
girl in Syria she's going to die
if we take tore away from the creep in
america
he's got a lot of other options for how
he can be a creep and starts talking
people
so if you're a bad person for various
definitions a bad person
I and you're willing to break laws or go
around social norms
you've got a lot of other options
besides what or provides
whereas there are very few tools out
there like two or
for honest a I'm
I'd like to say law-abiding but let's go
with our civilization
abiding citizens out there and
and and it's important to understand
that this hypothetical thing is actually
also true for certain values so and art
or developer meeting that we had in
Munich
recently that Syrian woman came to us
and thanked us for TOR she said
I'm from a city called homes you might
have heard about it it's not a city
anymore
I use tor my family you store we were
able to keep ourselves safe on the
Internet thanks to tor
so I wanted to come here to Munich to
tell you this
thank you for the work that you're doing
and for people who
this was their first ed meeting they
were completely blown away
to meet this person wow the stuff that
we're working on the really actually
really does matter they're real people
behind it and we were all
I think very touched by it and all of us
know someone who has been on the
receiving end
of people being jerks on the Internet so
this is a real thing with their real
people involved
and its really important understand that
if you removed two option for that woman
in Syria
for you here in Germany now that we know
whatever Snowden has told the world
those bad guys those jerks
for different values about they always
have options
but very rarely to all of us have
options to actually keep us safe
and tour is certainly not the only one
but right now
and we hope in this talk we'll see that
we are making the right rate of by
working on tor
one or the other child what are the
other talks that I i give to them or the
other stories that I give to them
are 10 the the big questions they always
ask me is
but what about terrorists are to helping
terrorists
and we can we can and we should talk
about
well what do you mean by terrorists
because in China they have a very
different definition of terrorist
and in gaza they have a very different
definition Nov terrorist in
I in america they're always thinking
other small number of people in some
Middle Eastern country or
are trying to blow up buildings or
something mom a bad guy
i think is his name yes that a in the
NSA slides
yes out so scenario 1
I want to build a tool that works for
millions of people
it will work for the next year and I can
tell you how it works so you can help me
evaluated
that stores problem scenario to I want
to belittle
tool that will work for the next two
weeks it will work for twenty people
and I'm not going to tell you about
there are so many more ways of solving
scenario to
than solving scenario 1: the bad guys
for all sorts of definitions a bad but
the bad guys have a lot more options
on how they can keep safe they don't
have to scale
doesn't have to last forever they don't
want peer review they don't want anybody
to even know that it's happening
so the the challenge the door has as we
want to build something
that works for everybody and that
everybody can analyze and learn about
at a much harder problem they're very
they're far fewer ways of solving that
so the terrorist ur they've got a lot of
options
that sucks we need to build tools that
can keep the rest for the world safe
and it's important really to try to have
some good rhetorical arguments I think
I mean we sort of put a few fax appear
one interesting point attention is that
people who really don't want anonymity
to exist in a practical sense maybe not
even in a theoretical human rights hands
either but definitely in a practical
sense
they're not really having honest
conversations about it for example this
doja study the department of justice in
the United States
they actually started to do a study
where they classify traffic moving
toward exit nodes which
it interesting that they were basically
probably wiretapping Exit now to do that
study
I wonder how they one about that but
when the last they came up with the
number three percent of the traffic
being bad and then they aborted the
study because they receive many DMCA
takedown notices
yeah apparently even a DMCA is a problem
to finding out
answers they have a university to run
the Torres it for them and they were
just starting out doing their study and
then the University started getting DMCA
takedowns
and said well we have to stop the
lawyers told us to stop
and the Department of Justice said were
the Department of Justice
keep doing it and then they turned it
off so
not sure how the balance of power goes
there but the initial results they were
looking towards were
about 3 percent at the traffic coming
out of that or exit node
I was bad but I haven't figure out what
they mean by bad
but I'll take it if it's three percent
and I think you know
we have of course II personally don't
like to use
the word war when talking about the
Internet
and I particularly dislike talking about
it when we talk about
actual issues have terrorism and I think
that we should talk about it in terms of
perception in conflict and one of the
most frustrating things
is the BBC actually has articles on
their website instructing people how to
use the so grow tent or together
to buy drugs we are very very
very seriously do not ever advocate that
for a bunch of reasons not the least of
which which is
that even a pic when is amazing its not
in anonymous currency
and it isn't the case that these web
sites are necessarily going again but it
will be tore I think
there will be the weakest link but the
fact that the BBC promotes that it's
because they generally have a man bites
dog
stew you could say that that's their
entire about or related
eco-system anything that could be just
kind of a little bit interesting
the run with it so they have something
to say about it and in this case they
literally were promoting and pushing for
people to buy drugs
which is crazy to me to imagine that and
that really impacts the way that people
perceive the door
project and the Tor network and what
we're trying to do is not that
particular thing
that is a sort of side effects occurs
what we want is for every person to have
the right to speak freely and right to
read
anonymously on the Internet and we also
need to keep in mind the different
incentive structures that they have
so BBC posted their first article about
Silk Road Indore
and the comment section was packed with
oh wow thanks
oh this is great well I don't have to go
to the street corner gunshot oh wow
thanks this is great
just comment after coming to people
saying thank you for telling me about
that
and then a week later they posted a
follow-up article saying
and we bought some and it was really
good
still have what motivation are they
doing here
and so they're they're goal in this case
is let's get more clicks doesn't matter
what it takes. doesn't matter what we
destroy what we're doing
for that has some serious problems
obviously because then they're
different structures that exist to
attack as part of the war on some drugs
and they want to show that their mission
is of course impacted by tor they want
to have an enemy that a campaign to
target on they want something sexy that
they can get funding for
so here's a here's a little funny a
story about an agent
as it has in the last point to show this
massive drop and Tor network load after
soap roadways bus is great because
everybody realizes of course that all
the enemy traffic in the world must be
for Alicia failed this was act at %uh
particular meeting where they were
trying to get more funding for this is a
US government person who basically said
I evaluated the Tor network load at
during the Silk Road bust
and I saw fifty percent network load
dropped when the Socceroo
when the Silk Road bus stop so I I
started out with him arguing
hola actually you know when there's a
huge amount of publicity about I don't
know if door is broken
we can understand it would be reasonable
that some poor people would stop using
tor for a little while
in order to wait for more facts to come
out and then we'll be more prepared for
it
but then I thought you know wait a
minute we've got the tour metrics
database we have
all of this data I love load on the
network
so then I went to look let's go actually
see if there was a 50 percent drop on
the Tor network
so the green line here is the capacity
above the Tor network over type so the
amount of bytes the release can push
I've we we're loading it down completely
and the Purple Line
is the number of bytes that are actually
handled on the network over time
can you guess where we're if you don't
look at the day to the bottom
can you show what that agent was talking
about
are as the agent totally full a shit
two-step after compression but if you
have a to anyone shouted out yeah
you in there no
ok but that's right it didn't go down by
fifty percent
wow he was completely wrong but
just for the record that's where he said
there was a dry the
and while we've taught you how to read
these graphs here's a graph above the
overall network growth
over the past three or four years so the
green line again as the amount of
capacity
and we've seen a bunch of people adding
fast relays recently after the Snowdon
I issues and we'll talk a little bit
later about are what other reasons
people are running more capacity lately
as the load on the network goes up okay
and then there is the dark web or the de
Puebla
or the whatever else the hell you call
it web and
again this comes back to media trying to
produces many articles are they can to
hear here's the basic
I'll give you the the primer on the
stark web thing statement one
the dark web is every web page out there
are the Google can't index
that's the definition in the dark web so
so every corporate database every
government
database every everything that you
access to the web browser at work or
whatever
all those things a girl can get to that
is the dark web a statement what
statement to
ninety-something percent have web pages
are in the dark web so these were both
well known fact a year ago
statement 3 that the media has added
this year
the only way to access the dark Weber is
through chore
these three statements together sell
more and more articles because its great
people. by then they're all shocked oh
my god the web is bigger than I thought
and it's all because it or so
really the reality of this is that it's
not
actually the case obviously that's a
completely laughable thing
and for everyone that's here not
necessarily people watching on the video
stream but for everyone here I think
you realize how ridiculous that is
entire setup is obviously a kind of
click great if you would call it
something like that there are a few
high profile hidden services actually
just as a show of hands
raise your hand if you run out or hidden
service right so
no one's ever heard your turn in service
on a certain way and these are the ones
that people heard of
and this is something which is kinda
fascinating
reality which is that these these four
sites
for these four entities have produced
most to the stories related
to deep gaping whatever web that you
wanna call the dark web
and in fact for the most part it's been
I would say up the top one for example
with WikiLeaks it's a positive example
and in fact with global leaks which is
something that Arturo Velasco and a
number of other
really great Italian hackers here been
working on global eats
they're deploying more and more
conservative but you also haven't heard
about for localize corruption
reporting and whistleblowing but the
news doesn't report about our terrace
great work
the news report on the farmers market on
freedom hosting and on
so gross and those things also bring out
a disproportionate amount of incredible
negative attention in the case of
freedom her saying we have a developer
Mike Perry whose
kind of the most incredible evil genius
alive today
i think is probably about to my period
right now if that would be my guess
and he was relentlessly attacked
because he happened to have a
registration for a company which had a a
an F in an H&amp;M wasn't
actually even close to what's up there
now and he was relentlessly attacked
because the topics that the other sites
have
as part of their customer base as part
of the things that they're pushing
online
be really pull on people's hearts in a
big way
and that sort of created a lot of stress
and in the the first issue
WikiLeaks created a lot of stress for
people working on tour in various
different ways
but for my Perry he was personally
targeted in as sort of COINTELPRO style
harassment and really sad and really sad
Series events
and of course the news also picked up on
that and some negative ways
and they're really really picked up on
that note to really be parted I think
you could call it a kind of culture
conflict that we're in right now the
farmers market has also quite an
interesting story which I think
you want to tell yet so I actually a
heard from a DEA person who was involved
in the
a eventual buster the farmers market
store so that a
long ago there was a website on the
internet and they sold drugs
oh my god and there are people who
bought drugs from this website and they
had no choice
tour was nowhere in the story it was
some web site in southeast asia
on and the DEA wanted to take it down so
they
they learned I mean the website was
public to public web server
so they sent some sort of letter to the
country that was in and the country that
was in said screw you
and then they said okay well I I guess
we can't take down the web server so
then they
are started try to investigate the the
people behind it and it turns out the
people behind it
use touch man so they were happily
communicating with each other very
safely
are so the folks in the US are sent a
letter to Canada
and then Canada made house may love it
will give them the entire database UHV
all the emails that these people and
sent on and then
a year or two later these people
discover tore and they're like hey we
should switch our website overt or and
then it'll be safe that sounds good
other DA people were watching them the
whole time looking for a good time to
bust them
are and then this was a separate or and
then six months later was a good time to
bust them
I so then there are all these newspaper
articles about how to or hidden services
are obviously broken
on and I the first time I heard the
story I was thinking to myself
are idiot drug sellers use Pay Pal get
busted
and a story up but they're actually
using Pay Pal correctly they they had
a innocent people around the world who
are receiving people payments and
turning it into some
Panama based the currency or something
so the the the better
less another story is ideo drug sellers
use Hotmail get busted
so there are there a lot of different
pieces have all of these don't use harsh
male
seriously to bad idea and don't use
things where
they have habit back during their
service or cooperating
with so-called lawful interception
orders because it tells you that their
system is not secure
and its clear that hush male falls into
that category
big day fundamentally have chosen that
that is what they would like to do and
they should have that reputation
and we should respect them exactly as
much as they deserve that's done use
their service
if you can especially if you're gonna do
this kinda stuff
or maybe what I mean is guys do that his
house now
but everybody else protect yourself
so the thing is that
not every single person is actually
stupid enough to use hash map
and so as a result we have started to
see some pretty crazy stuff happened
which we of course knew would happen and
we always
understood that this would be a vector
so in this case
this year we saw I think one of the
probably
not the most interesting exploits that
we've ever seen
but one of the most interesting expert
who ever seen deployed against
a broad-scale users and
we're not exactly sure who was behind it
though there was an FBI person
who went to court and Ireland and did in
fact claimed that they were behind it
the IP space that the exploit connected
back to was
either SAIC or NSA and I had an inner
I had an exchange with one of the guys
behind the hoop and exploit company
and he has on a couple occasions
mentioned writing exploits for TOR
browser
and what he really means is Firefox and
this is a serious problem of course if
they want to target a person though the
first they have to actually find them
so traditionally if you're not using tor
to go to your house
the plugins and year to go to the ISP
extreme negligence in here or there is
an interception with an MC catcher and
things like that
most abused techniques I'll talk about
on Monday with Claudio
I'm if you're interested am but
basically it's the same
they find out who you are then they
begin to tire you
when they serve your next flight this
year one of the differences is that they
had actually taken over it or hidden
service
and started to serve up an exploit from
that just
trying to exploit every single person
and visited the hidden service so there
was a period of time when you could
really badly troll all your friends by
just putting
a link up where who would load in an
iframe and they would have been
exploited
if they were running an old version of
Firefox an old version of Tor browser
which was an interesting twist they
didn't actually as far as we know
use bad exploit against anyone well it
was a fresh
zero-day but they did write it and they
did serve it up
and they gave the rest of the world the
payload to use against whoever they like
so when the FBI did this they basically
gave an exploit against Firefox and Tor
browser to the Syrian
electronic army couldn't have written
one even if they wanted to
this is a really interesting difference
between other ways that the FBI might
try to bust you
where they can localize the damage love
hitting untargeted
people who are otherwise innocent
especially
by we've asked Firefox try to integrate
some of these probes related things that
we've done we'd like to be able to be
more up to speed with Firefox
and they generally seem friendly to it I
think that's a fair
fair thing to say but we have the
synchronization
but even East with that the
synchronization we were still had a
what they were doing as far as we can
tell but they are actually at the point
where
the have hired probably some people from
this community the fuck you
and day writers exploits
answered them up and so that is a new
turn
we have not seen that before this year
and that's a really serious change
as a result we've obviously been looking
into Chrome which has a very different
architecture in some cases a
significantly harder to exploit in
Firefox
even with just very straightforward but
we should be very easy to exploit the
crown team has done a good job
we want to have a lot of diversity in
the different browsers but we have a
very strict set of requirements for
protecting
privacy what are other and there's a
whole design document up there
so just adding to run a web browser
together is not quite enough you need
you need some actual thoughts that have
been mostly by Mike parry and Aaron
Clark have been elucidated in the Tor
browser design document
so we are hoping to work on that if
anyone here would like to work on that
that's really something where we really
need to help because it's
there's really only one Mike Perry
literally and figuratively
okay another exciting topic people have
been talking about lately
is the diversity of funding a lot of our
funding comes from governments US mostly
but some other ones as well
because they have things that they want
us to work out so once upon a time
I when I was looking at fundraising and
how to get money I i would go to places
and I would say
we've got ten things we want to work on
if you
want to find one of these ten you can
help us at our priorities we
we really want to work on %uh
circumventing censorship
we really want to work on anonymity we
really want to work on tour browsers
safety
so if you can if you have funding for
one at the is then we'll focus on the
one that your
are most interested in so there's a
trade-off here up
on the one hand government funding is
good because we can do more thinks
that's great
the a lot of the stuff that you've seen
from tor over the past couple years
comes from people who are paid full-time
to be able to work on tor
and and focus on it and not have to
worry about where they're gonna pay
their rent or
or whether gonna get food on the other
hand it's bad because
I funders can influence our priorities
no there's no conspiracy
it's not that people come to us and say
here's money do a back door and so on
we're never gonna put any back doors
into or
ever maybe you could tell the story
about an really a high-pitched lady who
tried to get you to tell you that it was
your duty and then you explained
give me few more details
people have approached us obviously in
order to try to get us to do these types
of things
and this is a serious commitment that
the whole tower community
gets fired which is that we will never
ever put in a back door
and any time that we can tell that
something has gone wrong
we try to fix it as soon as possible
regardless
actually I would say for myself any
other consequences
that our commitment to protecting
anonymity our user base
extends beyond any reasonable commitment
actually
and we really believe that commitment
and there are people that have tried to
get us to change that tried to tell us
that alright
only because your living in the free
world and you're able to have a company
that and make a profit that you can even
right to suffer so come on do your duty
and of course when we tell them where
nonprofit
and that we're not gonna do it they're
completely dumbfounded for example
now I remember that discussion yes
haircut
this was a discussion with the US
Department of Justice person
I who basically said it's your the
congress has given
us the Department of Justice the right
to
backdoor everything and you
have a tool that you haven't made it
easy for us to back door
so it's your responsibility to fix it so
that we can use the privileges and
rights given us
by congress on you know surveilling
everybody
and you are taking advantage above the
situation that we've given you an
America where
you've got good freedom of speech and
you've got other freedoms and so on your
your your stealing from the country
you're cheating on the process
by not giving us the back door the
congress said we should have and then I
said actually we're a nonprofit
we work for the public good and then
then the conversation basically ended
she had no further than a sec
so part of what we need to do is
continue to make tools that are actually
safe
as tools rather than a lot of the other
systems out there
on the other hand I'll every funder
we've talked to lately
has interesting priorities they want to
pay for censorship resistance they are
paper outreach
education training and so on we don't
have any funders right now
who want to pay for better anonymity and
it's really important for some other
people we heard about in the last talk
that they have really good anonymity
against really large adversaries
and I'm not just talking about american
intelligence agencies there are a lot of
intelligence agencies around the world
who are trying to learn how to serve a
leveraging
so what should
tours role be here there are a lot of
people in the toward development
community who say
what we really need to do is focus on
writing good code
and will let the rest the world to curve
itself on
there's also a trade-off from some other
funders we have right now
where I I could go up and I could say a
lot
love really outrageous things that I
agree within that you agree with
I but some other funders might wonder I
if they should keep funding us after
that
so part of what we need to do is get
some funders
who are more comfortable with the
message is that everybody here
would like the world to hear so if you
know anybody who wants to help provide
actual freedom we'd love to hear from
you and it's important to understand the
resort %uh havin interesting
place in the world at the moment where
its easy to say
that we shouldn't be political and then
general
there shouldn't be politics and what
we're doing and it's also easy to
understand that that's crazy
when someone says that to an extent
because
the idea of having free speech having
the right to read having the ability to
reach
a website it is beyond the power the
state that is a very political thing for
many people and it is often the
privilege
up some where they don't even realize
that a political statement
and they suggest and they suggest
that we don't need to be political we
need to recognize the political context
that we exist and especially after the
summer snowden
understanding that there are almost no
tools
that can resist the NSA and GCHQ almost
none
we did not survive completely in the
Summer Sun
they were able to get some tore users
but they couldn't get all
to our users that's really important we
change the economic game for them
and that fundamentally is a political
issue
but please note that the solution is not
a partisan solution
where we say will some people are good
and some are bad you guys over there
and left her on the right you don't
deserve to have freedom
have speech you don't have the right to
read we aren't saying that we're saying
that the common good
everyone having news fundamental rights
protected in a practical way
is an important thing for us to build
one for all of us to contribute to
efforts
every person to have that his I think
the best kind of political solution we
can come up with
though it is a very controversial one in
some ways I think that
we can to actually do it unless everyone
really starts to agree with us and we
are making a lot of positive change in
this as we saw with the network graph
but this comes from mutual aid and
solidarity
which most the people in this room
provide and that diversity a user's
is actually technically what makes tour
say
you need to have activists in various
countries
and fault in russia right now and
law enforcement around the world you
need to have them all in the same
network
otherwise if I see that you're using tor
I can start getting why you're using tor
so we need that diversity abusers not
just
up for a perception perspective but for
actual technical perspective
we need to have all the different are
types of users out there
blending into the same system so that
they can keep each other say
so part of the the hobbies that each or
person has
we're all are getting better at our
reach to various communities
so I mentioned earlier that I talk to
law enforcement
are to try to teach them how these
things work turns out that having Jake
talk to law enforcement is not actually
the most effective way to convince the
most things
so I'm I'm I'm yeah you know my lawyer
give me some great advice but I can tell
you without breaking the privilege of
our other communications
but she says never miss a chance to shut
the fuck up and that I think really
really underscores why I should not talk
to police about why they also need
traffic analysis resistance reachability
network security privacy and anonymity
Rogers much much more diplomatic so at
the same time we have people talking
to domestic violence and abuse groups
and teaching them how to be safe
and at the same time we have falter
corporations learning how to be safe
online we hear
from large companies who are saying I
want to
put the entire our corporate traffic
overt or because we actually do have
adversaries and they actually are spying
on us and they do want to learn what
we're doing so how do we become safe
from the situation so part of what we
need is help from a love you
to become outreach for all of your
communities and get better at teaching
people about why privacy is important
for the communities that you're talking
to and learn how to use their language
and convince them that these things are
important and at the same time teach
them about the
other groups out there who care so they
can understand it's a bigger issue than
just whatever their
most focused on okay
so a while ago I wrote up a list of
three ways to destroy it or
I the first way which we've got a we
have a handle on it for a while the
first way is
change the laws for the policies are the
cultures are so that
anonymity is outlawed and we're pretty
good at fighting back
in government and policy in culture and
so on and saying no no there are there
good uses these things you can't
take them away from the world the second
way make ISP's hate hosting
exit relates and if more and more ISPs
say no I'm not gonna do that
then eventually the Tor network shrinks
reducing the anonymity it can provide
because there's not as much diversity
up where you might pop out to the Tor
network to go to the website
so I think we're doing pretty well
fighting that fight a we've known about
it for a while it's one we've been
focusing on for a long time
tore servers dotnet a lot of other
groups are doing great work
at building and maintaining
relationships with ISP's
but the third one is one that we haven't
focused on
as much as we should which is make
website hate
tore users so a growing number of places
are just refusing to hear from for use
at all
I Wikipedia did that a long time ago
Google gives you a captcha if you're
lucky
that's the best question ever feel like
that's a good setup
I'll cover this one next have
so Skype is another interesting example
here
if you run it or exit relay you try to
Skype with somebody
microsoft hangs up on you and the reason
for that is not that they say oh my god
or people are are abusing Skype
Microsoft pays some commercial company
out there to give them a blacklist they
don't even know what's on it
and the company put store exit IP's on
it and now a Microsoft black lists all
the tower exit relays and they don't
even know they're doing it they don't
even care
so as more and more of these
blacklisting companies
I exist we're more and more screwed
so we need help trying to I learn how to
teach all of these companies
how to accept users without thinking
that IP addresses
are the right way to identify people
there might also be
on point three a relationship here with
some other other points here
for example point for which is to say
that
when a company does not want to give you
location anonymity
maybe there's a reason for that I mean I
personally think that Wikipedia is great
I don't feel so great about Yelp and
about Google
most the time and I definitely don't
feel good about Skype
given what we've learned it makes sense
that they would demonstrate that they do
not respect
you as users and the Tor network as a
way to protect users from
them actually and to some of these
places will say that its beauty
basically only being
use for abuse often they won't have
metrics for it
and they will refuse to work with us to
come up with inventive solutions
like for example something where you
have to use
a a name system in some kind in the case
in Wikipedia
or something where you saw the capture
something where you have to have an
account something where your suit
anonymous
but you get to retain location privacy
and in
actually in a few cases it's probably
better that or is blocked because
they don't even provide secure loggins
when you're not using tor so it's not
necessarily always a good thing to use
the services anyway
so a net serve funny sense it could be
helpful that they're blocking tore
but we would like to improve those
things when one thing is to show that we
need to build some systems to get these
properties
and we need to show that it is the best
thing right now
that we all can use and we need people
that are working
with these companies with these
communities actually help us to
understand how we can better
server at torch immunity but
also but or community that overlaps with
their community
especially Wikipedia it for me
personally it kills me that the way that
I get to edit the wiki or should I edit
it
is that I have to send an email to
someone tell them in a county already
have
ask them to set a special flag in the
wiki pedia database and then I can login
and edit that's not really the ideal
solution
I think if I'm not being abusive on
Wikipedia I should be able to have
soon on a mess waiter at it I should be
able to anonymously connected I should
be able to do that from anywhere in the
world
especially when the local network
censored me and my only way to get
to the Wikipedia is to in fact you store
or something like it
so the last point on that who is this
one
at what was the joke the George main
yeah so I showing is you know
showing mister an enemy researcher and
he started yelling I P O I P O IPOs soon
as he saw this
graphite or users over time so in the
course of the week or so
we added about four or five million to
our clients to the network
and you would think allow the stalking
thing worked it's great
but actually some jerk in the Ukraine
signed up is $5 million node botnet
I mean one of the good things about this
is that we learned that the Tor network
scales to more than five million users
we've been working out a little early
and work we had to make some changes
there's for example the and/or
handshaking
which is using elliptic curves that is
something which
really helps to reduce the load on the
relays this is a up
pretty big change but there's a lot of
work to my Perry is done load balancing
lot of work by Nick Matthews and lotsa
changes the Tor network for
for scalability but if this had been
like a real attacker
to bomb it had been turned against it or
network it probably would have been
fatal
I think Inc really interesting details
that this was a bonnet for Windows
and microsoft has the ability to remove
things that they flagged as malicious
and so they were going around in
removing
tore clients from Microsoft Windows
users
that were part of this botnet now when
we talk for them
my understanding is that they only
removed when they were certain that it